this large language model app can answer
questions complete tasks summarize text
and write and run python code at the
real kicker it's free it's not using the
open AI API it is completely open source
in this video we're going to be speed
building the app and stacking a 7
billion parameter model a 13 billion
parameter model and a bunch more up
against open AI to see if they can even
get close one of the easiest ways to get
access to open source large language
models is through GPT for all through it
you can actually use a chat like
interface whilst running the models
locally on your machine the upside to
using the guis that'll actually download
the model weights to your machine which
means that you can then use it inside of
lanechain there's GUI based installers
available via the GPT for a website I've
also included detailed steps on how to
run the code if you want to get it up
and running yourself I'll get to that a
little bit later so first up I
downloaded and installed the GPT for all
GUI to my Windows machine the first time
I did this I wasn't paying attention so
I had no idea where the models would be
downloaded to pay special attention to
the default download folder for the
weeks if you Breeze through it like I
did you can bring it back up by checking
the download part in my case they will
say saved here I downloaded the Llama 13
billion snoozy model and a couple of
others to put them to the ultimate test
would these actually stack up against
the big guy now that I've got some model
weights downloaded I'm going to whip up
an app using streamlit this will allow
you to interact with the different llm
models through a simple user interface
we're going to blast through this pretty
quickly because it's pretty similar to
what we did inside of the Lang chain
crash course in the langchang crash
course we started out by creating a file
called app.pi This is where our llm
application is going to lift now the
first thing that we need to do is import
stream lit as St this is going to give
us our app development framework let's
add a comment app Dev framework and then
what we want to do is have a title so
we're going to say title actually we
don't need to set it to a variable so St
dot title I'm going to plug in a Emoji
because we've got to make it look sweet
and we're going to title it GPT for
y'all y'all which probably Escape that
perfect all right cool so this is the
title and then what we want to do is
let's start up our app just to make sure
this is where talking I can't imagine
this is broken right now so we can run
Streamliner app or streamlit run app.pi
this will open it up in a new browser
window perfect so we've got GPT for
y'all happening right now so that is our
title now if we wanted to change that
you could change it to whatever you
wanted to something a little bit more
appropriate for a business application
okay so that is our title the next thing
that we want to do is include a place
that we can actually pass through a
prompt so we're going to create a
variable called prompt so prompt holder
so this is the prompt text box and we
are going to set that equal to St dot
text input
if you had bigger text inputs you might
choose to go with text area I found text
input works pretty well and we are going
to include the label for this so we're
going to say plug in let me make sure my
head is not covering that now we're good
plug in your prompt yeah and if we go
and save and we go and refresh our app
again take a look so we've now got
somewhere that we can type in a prompt
right so I could say
um hey how's it going and eventually
when we hit enter on our keyboard we
want to do something right now it's not
doing anything because like you can see
that I'm hitting enter if I go and
change it if I hit enter it's running up
there you can see it really briefly
right we actually need to do something
or activate a trigger once we go and hit
enter so relatively easily so if we hit
enter do this
so we're going to say if prompt and then
all we need to do is right now for right
now we don't actually want to go and
import anything we'll get to that so
we're going to write st.write and we're
just going to write out our prompt so we
can at least see that we're doing
something we're getting a little bit of
feedback so we're going to say if we hit
enter then we're going to do whatever's
here right so that is our Baseline app
let's just go and test it out so if we
go and refresh so you can see it's
already printing out the output of our
prompt there so if I go and change it to
yo yo yo you can see that we are
outputting the output there that at
least gives us the shell for our GPT for
all app so we've got an app that we can
interact with but we haven't actually
done any llm stuff yet time to bring the
Thunder first up importing Lane chain
dependencies so we've got the shell up
and running but right now we haven't
actually done anything with Lang chain
this is where that changes so we're
going to jump back into our app and what
we're now going to do is first up import
a couple of dependencies so import
dependencies so we're first up going to
import the GPT for all class so from
langchain.l
lens we're going to import a GPT for all
so this is going to allow us to actually
leverage our GPT for all weights what we
also want to do is import The Prompt
template so from langchain dot actually
we don't need to go to a sub module
we're just going to import The Prompt
template Port we spell that right from
Lane chain there we go prompt template
and we're going to import the llm chain
so the prompt template is going to be
used for prompt formatting the link
chain llm chain is going to give us a
chain that we can execute perfect the
last thing that we want to do is the
path to or set up a variable to hold the
path to our weight so path to weights
we're going to create a variable called
path and set that equal to the area that
you've actually gone and set up your GPT
for or GUI to download way to in my
particular case it's inside of users
user app data local nomec.ai and GPT for
all so if I actually go to that path
I'm actually going to grab a specific
set of Weights so let me show you that
you can see I've actually got a couple
downloaded already now if you haven't
downloaded any you're probably not going
to see any bin files there but you can
actually choose which model that you
want to use so let's say for example I
wanted to use llama 13 billion 13
billion snoozy I could actually copy
that entire file path or file name and
then what we're going to do is we are
going to paste that into our path at the
end so this is actually going to give us
the full file path to our weights now
remember that in the documents video we
use the open AI llm module the core
change here is that we're now going to
use the GPT for all class Lane chain
supports a range of different llm
sources which makes it pretty
straightforward to sum them out as
needed I tried doing this initially with
hugging face Hub but notice that
inference was taking quite some time if
you'd like to see me do a video with
hugging face Hub let me know in the
comments below for now we're going to
stick with GPT for all though because
that's what I promised in this video so
the first thing that we need to do is
actually create an instance of our llm
so instance of llm so we're going to say
llm is equal to GP t for all and what we
need to do is we need to specify the
model and to that we are going to pass
through our path and we are also going
to set verbose to equal to true that are
another bunch of other parameters that
you can set this is the absolute minimum
that you need to write in order to get
GPT for all up and running what we then
want to do is create a prompt template
and I went through a bit more detail in
terms of prompt templates in the crash
course as well as the documents videos
so for now we're going to say prompt is
equal to prompt template and we want our
input variable
we're just going to set it to question
and then our actual template
e-l-a-t-e we're going to set that equal
to a multi-line string and we're going
to say our question is equal to or say
colon and then we can include our
question there and we'll structure and
say answer let me think that or step by
step so we could tweak this you could
change it from template based on a
little bit of prompt engineering you
could even say um let's go through this
let's think step by step cool that's our
template kind of set up so again you
could play around with this depending on
how you wanted to actually structure
your prompts I've kept it reasonably
simple we've just gone and said question
is equal to the question that we're
going to be passing through to our
prompt template and then the answer is
going to start out by saying let's think
step by step let's actually make it
let's think step by step then what we
can do is we all we really need to do is
set up our Lem chain and this is going
to bring our llm which is our GPT for
all model and our prompt together so
let's actually go and do that so we're
going to say our chain 9 is going to be
equal to our llm chain and our prompt is
going to be equal to our prompt template
which we just created over here and our
llm is going to be equal to our GPT for
all llm so we can paste that in there
beautiful and that is our llm chain now
done the Baseline llm chain was Now set
up all we needed to do was pass through
the prompt and using the run method
stack them up so we actually need to put
some of this into action right so we've
now gone and defined all the stuff but
right now we're not actually doing
anything with that prompt we actually
need to send it to our chain that we've
got over here super simple because we've
already set up the structures right all
we need to do is update our St dot write
area well first up we actually need to
pass our prompt us the prompt to the llm
chain and the way that we're going to do
that is we are going to run chain dot
run and we are going to be passing
through the prompt that we've got over
here to that that is going to return a
response so we're going to store that
inside of a variable over here so
response and we're going to set that
equal to whatever we get back from our
Channel what we then need to do is just
make sure that we write it back to our
screen so if I grab that response and
pass it through to St dot right here
that should effectively give us exactly
what we need so we're now let's just
quickly walk through the flow so we've
got our llm we've got our prompt
template both of those are sent through
to our llm chain then if our user types
in a prompt and hits enter then we
trigger anything that happens down here
what is going to happen down here is we
pass through the prompt to our llm chain
which we set up over there and then we
are going to write out the response that
we get back from our chain to the screen
the model weights that we defined in our
path variable pointed to the nomic AI
snoozy 13 billion parameter model if we
prompt our app let's say asking about
the fastest car in the world we should
get back a response and what do you know
it's identified the Bugatti Chiron
Supersport 300 plus is the fastest car
in the world just a tad faster than my
20 year old RAV4 now rather than just
looking at one model in isolation though
I wanted to see how some of these open
source ggml models stack up against each
other in open AI a designed six tests to
put our models through the first one
basic chat q a side note I'll share the
code for the comparison app a little
later let's establish a baseline with
open AI if we ask about the difference
between nuclear fusion and fission shout
out to James Spriggs for the info we get
a pretty coherent response open ai's
text DaVinci 003 calls out Fusion is
combining two or more Atomic nuclei and
fission as splitting any nuclear
scientists out there let me know whether
or not this actually checks out now what
if we ask Mosaic ml's 7 billion
parameter commercially licensable MPT
instruct model to be perfectly honest it
doesn't look too bad still calls out the
main idea around splitting and fusing
albeit with a focus on astrophysics the
thing is though this was an absolute
pain in the ah buttocks to get up and
running you see when I use the bass
prompt template that I wrote I got
responses that were about as good as me
giving a speech after a multi-pint pub
session gibberish after banging my head
against my desk for two and a half hours
I went for a run and figured maybe I
could reverse engineer how the GPT for
all GUI app work looking at the
underlying GPT for all Library I noticed
that the chat completion method used a
prompt template which clearly delineated
instructions prompts and responses so I
updated the prompt template to do the
same and well I'll show mpt's new
sunflower poem in a sec asking the same
question to the nomic AI trained 13
billion parameter non-commercially
licensed llama inspired model called
snoozy oh my God that's quite a mouthful
we got great responses as well short
simple and to the point and very similar
to what text DaVinci 003 was generated
what if we wanted to write an email
telling our customers about a sale
though open ai's text DaVinci Breeze
store pretty quickly even mentioning a
25 discount MPT did pretty well here as
well creating a practical and wild
structured template with placeholders
for the customer's name your name and
company name there was a weird set of
brackets and a dollar sign that it
generated at the start of every response
so if you use this model in isolation
this would be pretty easy to strip out
some string slicing snoozy did even
better at this and even offered up a
discount code to our customers and
speaking of discounts you can get 50 off
my full stack machine learning course
the courses from Nick for the next week
in it you'll learn how to build
production grade machine learning models
from the ground up and I'm about to add
a lane chain project to the course next
week grab the course now and you'll get
access to the videos as I release them
if you're already a student you'll get
immediate access and if you buy it and
you don't like it don't stress just ping
an email to Nick courses from nick.com
within 30 days and I'll give you a
complete refund no questions asked as
soon as you send that through and if
you've got any questions shoot me an
email at that same location and I'll get
back to you now how about a poll text
DaVinci is a modern day Shakespeare so
asking it to write a poem about
sunflowers was a sure thing it goes into
a literary exposition of those towering
golden helianthus MPT however begun
hallucinating and mistook sunflowers for
sunnies maybe there's a metaphor
somewhere there I'm not so sure about
those results but it is an interesting
read you let me know snoozy comes
through with the goods though even
rhyming throughout and boom we now have
an llm app using open source models
we're going to call it no pin AI
t-shirts coming soon interestingly when
you download the models through the GPT
for all GUI there's information about
whether the models are commercially
licensable which guides you as to
whether or not you can bake these into
your startup or business app I wish I
could stop while I'm ahead but I can't
so we're going to take this further I
originally planned on building a trading
integration with an algo trading
platform but travel has been kicking my
butt let me know what other llm ideas
you've got so I'm going to refactor the
app to use the python tool chain with an
open AI app all we really have to do is
swap out the llm chain with a python
agent before we do any swapping out what
we actually need to do is import a
couple of additional things so we're
going to go from
langchain.agents.agent toolkits we are
going to import the create python agent
function where is it create python agent
perfect and then what we also want to do
is we want to import the python tool
chain so let's say python tool chain
Imports so we're going to go from
langchain.tools dot python dot tool
we're going to import the python reple
tool perfect so that will give us the
two main dependencies that we need to
actually get our python app now up and
running while we're at it we can
actually get rid of the prompt template
in llm chain because we're not going to
use those anymore so I'm just going
going to delete those we could also
comment them out if we didn't want to
delete them completely and we can
actually get rid of our llm chain and
our prompt template now keep in mind
that this is kind of optional you don't
need to go down this route but I do like
the agent executor type tool chain from
linkchain so create a python agent and
we're going to say python agent is equal
to create python agent all we need to do
to that is pass through our llm and we
also need to create a tool set and we
are going to set that equal to our
python reple tool this actually means
that you can trigger python not only
right get it to write python but
actually trigger python via this
LinkedIn agent I think it's personally
absolutely amazing and we're also going
to set verbose equal to true and then
all we really need to do is swap out our
chain down here with our python agent
now we should be able to go and use our
python agent as opposed to our basic llm
chain before dumping the open source
llms I had two more tests dropping a
block on Formula One over to open AI got
us a pretty neat summary of the
Motorsport racing event MPT instructs
seemed to maybe have reached its limit
here although I'm not completely sure
whether or not this was due to an
incompatibility with the GPT for all
class or something else I'm sure with a
little fine tuning it could probably
work but I did try with varying hyper
parameters adjusting temperature and
sampling settings it just seemed to
bridge too far it was generating Arabic
characters and started hallucinating
referring to a death in the sport was
this it for open source llms nope snoozy
came through with a good generating an
abstractive and coherent summary of the
Wikipedia extract at the same time I
tested out another llama 13 billion
parameter derivative vicuna this time
trained by some prominent us
universities again generating a pretty
short and sweet summary it was killing
me that MPT wasn't quite working along
the way I did try the Basin chat models
with the GPT for all class the chat
model didn't seem to return results this
is probably a work in progress to be
honest they seem to have the same issues
that instructed going a little bit wild
one of the things I've been testing out
at work has been few shot prompting so I
figured hey let's give it a crack here
the test case was to look at a sequence
of numbers in a evaluated condition here
the prompt outlines the numbers 15 32 5
13 82 7 and 1 and notes that the odd
numbers in the group add up to an even
number ideally we will run our model to
respond true or false fifteen plus five
plus thirteen plus seven plus one add up
to 41 which would render this condition
as false and boom Tech DaVinci comes
through with the goods snoozy however
got caught snoozing here and
unfortunately couldn't replicate the
results using the same problem
admittedly this Chain of Thought
reasoning is quite complicated even for
most modern llms the kuna however
managed to get the samurai which to be
honest is kind of amazing unfortunately
its Chain of Thought LED it to the wrong
conclusion still not a bad effort this
brings us to the final tests using the
llms inside of a python agent with
self-debugging I wanted to see if openai
could calculate the 12th number in a
standard Fibonacci Sequence now this
one's Up For Debate the 12th number in a
Fibonacci Sequence will be 89 if you
started from zero which from my two
minute Googling seems correct but it
would be 144 if you started from one
with without clarifying text DaVinci
comes up with 144 right you let me know
the big snooze dog however after 17
minutes of setting my CPU on fire came
through with 89 I know crazy mind you
even though I got the answer right it
took so long running on CPU that I
managed to make lunch while it was
recording this demo snippet I did see
there's a way to run GPT for all on GPU
so maybe next video all the code to get
this up and running is available via my
GitHub account in the description below
I've included really detailed
instructions inside the readme as well
as the requirements so txt file so you
know exactly what libraries and versions
I use I'd love to know if you're
building any interesting llm apps if you
do manage to build them and create a
video make sure to tag me on Twitter and
or LinkedIn I'll include my handles
there I'd love to see what you're
getting up to and if you're Keen to
continue Ulan change only check out the
lane chain crash course that we did up
here